<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Vikram Ramakrishnan &#8211; Infinite Possibilities</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/mySite/author/vikram-ramakrishnan/feed/?simply_static_page=29578" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Dare to Dream</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 17:20:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Managing Up</title>
		<link>/2024/04/27/managing-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 17:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In today&#8217;s fast-paced corporate world, achieving success extends beyond individual abilities or team management skills. It also depends on your capacity to effectively manage upwards. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In today&#8217;s fast-paced corporate world, achieving success extends beyond individual abilities or team management skills. It also depends on your capacity to effectively manage upwards. This often overlooked skill, known as &#8216;<strong><em>Managing Up</em></strong>,&#8217; can be a game-changer for career advancement and organizational success. In this article, we&#8217;ll delve into the essence of <em>managing up</em>, why it&#8217;s crucial, and how to implement it.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What does it mean?</h2>



<p><strong><em>Managing up </em></strong>is a strategic approach to fostering a relationship of trust and influence with your superiors. It involves understanding their priorities, communication styles, and expectations, and aligning your own work and communication accordingly, ultimately optimizing success for both you and your manager.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s also important to clarify what <em>managing up</em> is <strong>NOT</strong>:</p>



<ul>
<li>It&#8217;s not about<strong><em> managing your manager</em></strong> in a controlling sense, but rather about enhancing mutual understanding and productivity.</li>



<li>It&#8217;s not about <strong><em>manipulation or flattery</em></strong> but rather fostering a mutually beneficial partnership that enables both parties to succeed.</li>



<li>It&#8217;s not about <strong><em>circumventing management hierarchy</em></strong> to make decisions, but rather enhancing collaboration and decision-making within it.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why is it Important?</h2>



<p>Despite its critical role in workplace dynamics, managing up is often overlooked and rarely taught. Effective management upwards is key to advancing your career and achieving your professional goals. By proactively managing up, you can:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Gain Support and Resources</strong>: Building a strong rapport with your superiors can lead to increased support for your projects, access to resources, and opportunities for career advancement. </li>



<li><strong>Enhance Communication: </strong>Clear and effective communication with your higher-ups ensures alignment on goals and expectations, reduces misunderstandings, and fosters a culture of transparency and trust. </li>



<li><strong>Influence Decision-Making:</strong> When you understand your manager&#8217;s priorities and concerns, you can tailor your proposals and recommendations to resonate with their objectives, increasing the likelihood of buy-in and support. </li>



<li><strong>Navigate Organizational Politics:</strong> Every workplace has its politics and dynamics. Managing up allows you to navigate these complexities with finesse, ensuring that your voice is heard and your contributions are recognized.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to <em>Manage Up</em> Effectively</h2>



<p>In an environment where technical skills are often prioritized over management skills, the likelihood of encountering a less-than-ideal manager is high, making mastering the art of managing up essential for navigating professional challenges effectively. </p>



<p>Managers are humans too and are susceptible to all the complexities that makes each one of us.</p>



<p>Here are some steps on how to effectively <em>Manage Up.</em></p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Understand their Goals &amp; Priorities:</strong> Spend time to understand what their most important KPI is and what success means to them in the eyes of their management. When you don&#8217;t have straightforward answers to some of these questions, use your observations and the knowledge of the environment to fill in the missing pieces.</li>



<li><strong>Understand their work style and Communication Preferences</strong>: This is extremely important to improve the working relationship with your manager. It&#8217;ll also be the difference between you being the go-to person and a pest. Work Style &amp; Communication preferences vary and you can understand these by talking to them or observing them at work. Focus on the details &#8211; how do they like the status report structured, do they prefer email updates on Slack messages, Would they prefer you ack the message from stakeholders even if you don&#8217;t have the complete solution ready for them at this time, <em>how do they view punctuality and meeting attendance and meeting invite responses</em>, etc.</li>



<li><strong>Adapt your style to suit them</strong>: While this is easier said than done, understand that their success also depends on your success and they will equally adapt as mutual trust is built. I&#8217;ve found it easier when this is done in small bits. Start by synchronizing styles for the most important aspects and work your way down. Adapting does not mean that you completely change or forego your own style of working.</li>



<li><strong>Build Trust</strong>: I&#8217;ve mentioned before that building trust in any relationship requires, the <strong>3 C&#8217;s</strong> &#8211; <strong>Character, Competence, and Communication</strong>. Be consistent and keep your promises, build competence, and exhibit an extreme ownership mindset. Managers rarely like surprises, so be proactive in communicating statuses and ask for help when you need it. Let them know soon enough if something is falling apart and provide your thoughts on what we could do to mitigate problems.</li>



<li><strong>Be Solutions Oriented</strong>: Rather than be the person who can find and articulate all the problems, be the one who also provides what you think are possible solutions. This not only shows your resourcefulness but also highlights your competence and intention to do the right thing.</li>



<li><strong>Seek &amp; Provide Feedback:</strong> Once enough trust is built in a relationship, you can both seek and provide feedback to improve the working relationship. While <em>seeking feedback</em>, Reduce cognitive load and make it easy for them to give you feedback. Always set clear context without assuming anything and ask specific questions. For example, Rather than say &#8211; &#8220;<em>Can you help me on how to think about setting goals/expectations for engineers</em>&#8220;, Say, &#8220;<em>I</em> drafted these role expectations for engineers<em>, can you review and provide feedback on what you think is missing or could be done better</em>&#8220;. When providing feedback, identify the areas where you can genuinely help and then participate. Know the right time and place to provide feedback and bring it up there so it&#8217;s more effective.</li>



<li><strong>Set up expectations on how you&#8217;d like to be <em>Managed</em></strong>: Managers come in many styles and it&#8217;s important that you also set expectations on the best way they can manage you and help you do your best work. Be specific on what you need and respectfully bring it up. Give them time to adapt to your style and needs. For example, you may have a specific time of day when you are most productive and don&#8217;t want distractions. Talk to them about it and assure them that your availability when needed is not going to be an issue for them or your team.</li>
</ol>



<br><hr class="flaired">



<p>In conclusion, mastering the art of managing up is essential for career success and organizational effectiveness. By understanding your manager&#8217;s preferences, communicating effectively, and aligning your goals with theirs, you can build a strong relationship based on trust, mutual respect, and shared success. Embrace the challenges as opportunities for growth, and approach managing up with enthusiasm and intentionality.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Additional Reading</h2>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://hr.ucmerced.edu/content/managing-what-it-and-why-do-it" target="_blank">https://hr.ucmerced.edu/content/managing-what-it-and-why-do-it</a><br><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://houseofmangalam.com/blogs/camphor-tales/story-of-lord-vishnu-narad-muni" target="_blank">https://houseofmangalam.com/blogs/camphor-tales/story-of-lord-vishnu-narad-muni</a><br><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.purewow.com/money/types-of-bosses-tips" target="_blank">https://www.purewow.com/money/types-of-bosses-tips</a><br><a href="https://www.idealist.org/en/careers/managing-up-how-to-provide-feedback" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.idealist.org/en/careers/managing-up-how-to-provide-feedback</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From IC to a Manager &#8211; Navigating the transition into Management</title>
		<link>/2024/03/24/from-ic-to-a-manager-navigating-the-transition-into-management/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 07:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Embarking on the journey from an Individual Contributor (IC) role to a managerial position marks a significant milestone/decision in one&#8217;s career. Lately, I&#8217;ve observed a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Embarking on the journey from an Individual Contributor (IC) role to a managerial position marks a significant milestone/decision in one&#8217;s career. Lately, I&#8217;ve observed a growing trend of individuals grappling with this transition amidst the ever-shifting currents of the workplace.</p>



<p>As I reflect on my journey, I&#8217;m transported back to that moment over a decade ago when I made the leap from being an accomplished lead engineer on PayPal&#8217;s Core Platforms team to assuming the mantle of a manager within the same team. The questions, uncertainties, and challenges that punctuated that juncture continue to resonate with many who find themselves at a similar crossroads today.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity has-blush-light-purple-gradient-background has-background is-style-default"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Address the WHY?</h2>



<p>Understanding the motivations behind your decision to transition into a management role is paramount, as it sets the foundation for your long-term success. Consider the following questions:</p>



<p><strong>What are your motivations driving this transition?</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><em>Are you drawn to the potential for accelerated career growth that management offers compared to an individual contributor role?</em></li>



<li><em>Has your current leader recognized leadership qualities in you and offered you the role based on your demonstrated behaviors?</em></li>



<li><em>Are you considering the switch because your peers have expressed confidence in your managerial potential, and you&#8217;ve been exhibiting behaviors that resonate with effective leadership?</em></li>



<li><em>Do you believe that your skills and ambitions are better aligned with the responsibilities of a successful manager?</em></li>
</ul>



<p>You may have <strong><em>more than one reason</em></strong> from the above example or some other completely different reason, but it&#8217;s important that you spend time thinking about it honestly as it&#8217;ll guide your progress and help identify areas that you need to focus on.</p>



<p><strong><em>One important caveat</em></strong> to bear in mind is that if you&#8217;re considering this transition solely for the sake of growth opportunities and nothing else, it&#8217;s crucial to pause and reconsider. Making this decision based solely on perceived advancement prospects can potentially compromise both your effectiveness in the role and your long-term well-being. It&#8217;s worth noting that many corporations offer parallel career tracks that allow individual contributors to experience significant growth and development similar to those in managerial positions. Take a moment to reassess your motivations and consider the broader implications before proceeding.</p>



<br><hr class="flaired">



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Identify Necessary Skillsets</h2>



<p>It&#8217;s crucial to identify the skillsets required for a successful transition into management and assess your current proficiency level, as well as your plans to learn or enhance these skills.</p>



<p><strong>Effective Communication</strong>: This will serve as your superpower in your new role. Unlike your code, which spoke for itself as an individual contributor, your ability to communicate effectively, both orally and in writing, will be essential for managerial success.</p>



<p><strong>Strategic Thinking:</strong> Managers must navigate the organizational landscape strategically, understanding overarching objectives, defining priorities, and anticipating trends. Unlike individual contributors, who focus on depth, managers must take a breadth-first approach, making trade-off decisions in an ever-changing ecosystem.</p>



<p><strong>Decision Making &amp; Dealing with Ambiguity:</strong> Managers must be comfortable making decisions with incomplete information and be willing to revisit and adjust decisions as needed.</p>



<p><strong>Conflict Resolution:</strong> Managers are responsible for handling conflicts within the team and across stakeholders diplomatically to maintain productivity and progress.</p>



<p><strong>Time Management:</strong> Effective time management, including prioritization and delegation, is essential for balancing multiple responsibilities in managerial roles.</p>



<p><strong>Emotional Intelligence:</strong> Understanding and addressing the emotional needs of the team and building trust are crucial for fostering high-performance team dynamics.</p>



<br><hr class="flaired">



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Assess your comfort to some hard truths of management</h2>



<p><strong>Accountability vs. Delegation: </strong>While you&#8217;re accountable for the team&#8217;s results, you won&#8217;t be executing all the work yourself. Success hinges on your ability to delegate effectively and empower others to deliver.</p>



<p><strong>Impact on Others:</strong> Your actions as a manager will significantly impact the happiness and well-being of your team members. Their success and satisfaction are intertwined with your effectiveness as a leader.</p>



<p><strong>Delayed Gratification:</strong> Unlike the immediate feedback of resolving technical issues, the outcomes of management efforts may take months or even years to materialize. Patience and long-term vision are essential.</p>



<p><strong>From Tech Debt to Management Debt:</strong> Transitioning from handling technical challenges to managing people introduces a new set of responsibilities, including addressing &#8220;management debt&#8221; such as team dynamics and performance issues.</p>



<p><strong>Shift in Focus: </strong>Your primary focus will shift from coding and architecture to activities like conducting 1:1 meetings, setting performance goals, fostering cross-functional collaboration, and delivering presentations.</p>



<p><strong>Different Skill Set:</strong> Managing people requires a distinct skill set from managing code. Formal authority alone is insufficient to drive change; effective leadership involves understanding and motivating individuals.</p>



<br><hr class="flaired">



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Charting the Course</h2>



<p><strong>Identify Relevant Training Opportunities:</strong> Work with your leaders to Explore available training programs, workshops, or resources that can help you develop essential management skills. Look for opportunities that align with your learning objectives and career goals, such as leadership development courses or mentorship programs.</p>



<p><strong>Trial Period or Exploration:</strong> Consider trying out aspects of management in a temporary or experimental capacity before committing to a permanent transition. This could involve shadowing a manager, leading a small project or team initiative, or volunteering for leadership roles in cross-functional projects to gain firsthand experience and assess your suitability for the role.</p>



<p><strong>Contingency Planning:</strong> Anticipate potential challenges or obstacles that may arise during the transition process and develop contingency plans to mitigate them. Identify potential rollback options or exit strategies, such as revisiting your original role or seeking alternative career paths, in case the transition does not proceed as planned.</p>



<p><strong>Feedback and Reflection:</strong> Seek feedback from peers, mentors, or managers throughout the transition process to identify areas for improvement and ensure alignment with organizational expectations.</p>



<br><hr class="flaired">



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Things to remember</h2>



<p>Here are some important reminders to keep in mind:</p>



<p><strong>Role Modeling Behaviors:</strong> Remember that your actions as a manager will set the tone for your team. Be mindful of the behaviors you exhibit, as your team members will often emulate your approach to work, communication, and collaboration.</p>



<p><strong>Exhibiting Vulnerability:</strong> Embrace vulnerability and acknowledge that you don&#8217;t have all the answers. It&#8217;s okay to seek input from your team, admit mistakes, and ask for help when needed. This fosters a culture of openness, trust, and continuous learning within your team.</p>



<p><strong>Seeking Feedback: </strong>Actively solicit feedback from your team members on your leadership style, communication effectiveness, and areas for improvement. Constructive feedback can provide valuable insights for personal and professional growth and strengthen team dynamics.</p>



<p><strong>Networking Within the Company:</strong> Cultivate strong relationships and networks within your organization. Building rapport with colleagues from different departments can be invaluable for gaining support, sharing insights, and navigating challenges effectively, especially during times of crisis.</p>



<p><strong>Thinking About Systems and Processes:</strong> Look beyond day-to-day tasks and consider the broader systems and processes within your team and organization. Identifying areas for optimization, streamlining workflows, and implementing best practices can improve efficiency, effectiveness, and overall team performance.</p>



<p><strong>Finding a Mentor or Coach:</strong> Consider seeking guidance from experienced mentors or coaches who can offer support, advice, and perspective as you navigate the challenges of management. Their insights and expertise can help accelerate your development and enhance your effectiveness as a leader.</p>



<p><strong>Maintaining Technical Skills:</strong> Being a manager doesn&#8217;t mean you abandon your technical skills. You can still contribute by picking up small, non-urgent tasks, or assisting with technical challenges when needed. This not only supports your team but also demonstrates your commitment to staying engaged with the technical aspects of the work.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>Relating to an old Indian proverb, Don&#8217;t aspire to be a banyan tree leader who shields &amp; protects the team in all situations. Remember that while shade is great, there can be no growth if there&#8217;s no exposure to sunlight. Be the guiding light that empowers others to flourish on their own.</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>In conclusion, transitioning from an individual contributor to a management role is a significant step in your career journey. By understanding your motivations, honing essential skill sets, acknowledging the challenges ahead, and charting a clear execution plan, you can navigate this transition with confidence and success. Remember, the path to becoming an effective manager is not without its obstacles, but with dedication, resilience, and a willingness to learn and grow, you can unlock new opportunities for personal and professional fulfillment. Embrace the journey ahead, and may it lead you to new heights of leadership and accomplishment. <strong><em>Remember, your job is not to create followers, your job is to create more leaders.</em></strong></p>



<br><hr class="flaired">



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Further Reading</h2>



<p>&#8220;<strong><em>Management Skills: New Manager Training</em></strong>&#8221; (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.udemy.com/course/the-new-manager-managing-people-teams-processes/" target="_blank">Udemy</a>). <br>&#8220;<strong><em>Becoming a Manager: Transitioning from Individual Contributor to Leader</em></strong>&#8221; (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.linkedin.com/learning/make-the-move-from-individual-contributor-to-manager/" target="_blank">LinkedIn Learning</a>). &#8212; <br>&#8220;<strong><em>Conflict Resolution in Leadership and Talent Management</em></strong>&#8221; (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.udemy.com/course/conflict-resolution-leadership/" target="_blank">Udemy</a>) &#8211; <br>&#8220;<strong><em>Time Management Fundamentals</em></strong>&#8221; (<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/learning/time-management-fundamentals-14548057/the-power-of-managing-your-time?u=2120684" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">LinkedIn Learning</a>) </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 18/Nov/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/11/18/friday-musings-18-nov-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 16:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’ve read. Engineering Management: The Pendulum or the Ladder – I’ve personally encountered (even just a couple weeks ago) the question from senior engineers on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-is-layout-1 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Articles I’ve read.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://charity.wtf/2019/01/04/engineering-management-the-pendulum-or-the-ladder/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Engineering Management: The Pendulum or the Ladder</a> – I’ve personally encountered (even just a couple weeks ago) the question from senior engineers on whether they should explore Engineering management. This article shares many of points that I share personally and provides a way for engineers to analyze and determine how to move forward. While I don’t agree with some of the points mentioned in the article around skill deterioration, it still has a lot of valuable information that’ll help engineers evaluate career options.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Videos I Watched</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=evUfG3lrk5U" target="_blank" rel="noopener">What Happens If A Star Explodes Near The Earth?</a> – Another great video from Veritasium that proves that educational content can definitely be made in a very entertaining, crisp and joyful way. I learnt a lot of astronomy 101, long forgotten from my days at school. I wish schools adopt these techniques.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Podcasts I’m Listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://podcasts.google.com/feed/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5mZWVkYnVybmVyLmNvbS9Xb3JrbGlmZVdpdGhBZGFtR3JhbnQ/episode/MTAwMDU4NjE2MzQyMA?hl=en-IN&amp;ved=2ahUKEwj3_MDf-7f7AhUS6XMBHR_2Dw0QjrkEegQIIxAF&amp;ep=6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The problem with setting goals, with NFL linebacker Emmanuel Acho</a> – From Adam Grant’s Work Life Podcast, this is an interesting perspective on Goal setting and why we should pursue a life of significance instead of a goal based one and how that would be built-in with meaning and purpose becoming a source of motivation and propelling us towards success.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Tech Readings  </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/newsroom/news/intel-introduces-real-time-deepfake-detector.html#gs.ikckve" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel&#8217;s FakeCatcher</a> – You’ve heard me share in the past about how the latest advancements in AI around GPT-3, DALL-E2, Phenaki etc can potentially help create Deepfakes and why we needed another powerful AI to help us discern the difference. This was Intel’s announcement a couple days ago doing exactly the same. The tech behind this is interesting and accuracy rates are 96%!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>In a world where you can be Anything, Be Kind!</p>
<cite>Anon</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 11/Nov/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/11/11/friday-musings-11-nov-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 10:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=476</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’ve read. Technology that lets us “speak” to our dead relatives has arrived. Are we ready? – Personally, I believe tech like this would only [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-is-layout-2 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Articles I’ve read.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/10/18/1061320/digital-clones-of-dead-people/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Technology that lets us “speak” to our dead relatives has arrived. Are we ready?</a> – Personally, I believe tech like this would only worsen grief than help. With AI getter significantly better each day, there’s going to be more dilemmas like these that we need to be prepared to handle. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Videos I Watched</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z2Y0GMCFWq0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Could one vaccine protect against everything?</a> – This is the same question I had when taking 3 shots of the COVID vaccine. I wonder how a world without diseases would look like and what would happen to the entire healthcare sector (apart from these vaccine makers) when this becomes true.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Podcasts I’m Listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://hubermanlab.com/dr-layne-norton-the-science-of-eating-for-health-fat-loss-and-lean-muscle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Layne Norton: The Science of Eating&#8230;</a> – From the Huberman Lab podcast, this is by far the most comprehensive information I’ve seen on diet, nutrition, Health &amp; the entire science behind it. Dr. Layne and Dr. Huberman cover a wide variety of important topics in this really long form episode, but you can find timestamps to sections that you can use to know about things you feel important.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Tech Readings  </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://blog.kagi.com/age-pagerank-over" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Age of PageRank is Over!</a> – With search patterns increasingly moving over from traditional search engines to products like TikTok, Instagram etc, it’s only natural that we’ll very soon have AI powered, hyper-personalized search systems that’ll determine what I see, read, use and recommend.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>You don’t stop having fun because you get old; You get Old because you stop having Fun</p>
<cite>Anon</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 04/Nov/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/11/04/friday-musings-06-nov-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 11:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’ve read. How to Think for yourself – In this article, Paul Graham talks about importance of independent thinking. He also lists out what it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-is-layout-3 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Articles I’ve read.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/think.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to Think for yourself</a> – In this article, Paul Graham talks about importance of independent thinking. He also lists out what it means to be an independent thinker and the components of independent thinking and how we can nurture it.  I resonate with the thought that you are largely influenced by the kind of people you surround yourself with, so be open to diverse experiences, meeting and learning from new people.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Videos I Watched</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PXwStduNw14" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mathematics is the sense you never knew you had!</a> – I wish I had a Maths teacher like Eddie woo. In this inspiring TED talk he makes a case for why Mathematics is a sense just like touch &amp; sound and in the process inspires us to think differently about it. I wish schools taught these early on.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Books I’m re-reading</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15824358-the-first-90-days" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The First 90 days</a> – This book is a roadmap for how to navigate career transitions, organizational changes and internal promotions in a way that helps speed up the process of you becoming effective, faster and smarter.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Tech Readings  </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://architecturenotes.co/redis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Architecture Notes &#8211; Redis</a> – Architecture Notes is quickly becoming my go to place to reinforce fundamentals. I like the way the content is organized and presented in an effective way to makes learning fun.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>The world suffers a lot. Not because of the violence of bad people but because of the silence of good people</strong></p>
<cite>Napolean</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 28/Oct/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/10/28/friday-musings-28-oct-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’ve read. Non-linear workdays changing the shape of productivity – 9 to 5 work model is dead and as the world shifted to the hybrid [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-is-layout-4 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Articles I’ve read.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20220928-the-non-linear-workdays-changing-the-shape-of-productivity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Non-linear workdays changing the shape of productivity</a> – 9 to 5 work model is dead and as the world shifted to the hybrid work model employees now can craft their work schedules that suits them the best and takes into account their natural working rhythms. While greater flexibility will lead to greater productivity, it is important to have a clearly defined process and guideposts that prevent employees from straying too far away from a collaborative working schedule.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Videos I Watched</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FWTNMzK9vG4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Why you procrastinate even when it feels bad</a> – I’m a master procrastinator and have been trying hard to overcome it for many years now (maybe procrastinating too much the actions required to overcome procrastination!) While I’ve gotten progressively better it’s important to understand the underlying reasons for why we put off things so we can learn to become better. This video talks about the importance of balancing emotions and how they can affect why we put off certain things and what we can do to change.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Podcasts I Listened</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://hbr.org/video/6312276697112/how-to-work-with-a-passiveaggressive-coworker-the-harvard-business-review-guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to Work with a Passive-Aggressive Coworker</a> – From the HBR channel, this is an 8 min video episode with some great tips to deal with passive aggressive folks at work. We’ve all been there on both sides of the table and understanding this a bit more can help us all become a bit better.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Tech Readings  </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://roadmap.sh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Career Roadmaps for Developers</a> – By far one of the best organized contents I’ve seen to help developers in picking up a path and guide their learning. Best part – it’s open source, so if you want to add something you don’t see and think it’ll be useful for the community, submit a PR.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow"><p>Don’t be fooled by the calendar. There are only as many days in the year as you make use of. One man gets only a week’s value out of a year while another man gets a full year’s value out of a week.</p><cite>Charles Richard</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 21/Oct/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/10/21/friday-musings-21-oct-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 08:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’ve read. How much would you pay for a box that beeps! – This article had interesting nuggets on how to pitch a product to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-is-layout-5 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Articles I’ve read.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://jitha.substack.com/p/sunday-reads-164-how-much-would-you" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How much would you pay for a box that beeps!</a> – This article had interesting nuggets on how to pitch a product to the customer and set the price for it. It underscores the fact that customers don’t buy your product for its cutting-edge spec or features, they are buying it for solving their problem, so focus on the problem and you’ll never have to worry about lack of customers. This is applicable for everything that we do, day in and day out.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Videos I Watched</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IV3dnLzthDA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Man Who Accidentally Killed The Most People In History</a> – How did one man’s effort or a specific business’s interest create a long standing health problem and environmental catastrophe of the modern world is the premise of this video. I personally learnt a lot of new and interesting things in the video. Some parts chemistry, some parts psychology and a bit of economics!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Podcasts I Listened</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/thriving-in-the-face-of-contradiction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thriving In The Face Of Contradiction</a> – Another good one from Hidden Brain. From the podcast excerpt &#8211; “<em>We all face tough decisions in life, whether we’re juggling the demands of work and family or deciding whether to take a new job. These situations often feel like either/or choices. But psychologist <a href="https://lerner.udel.edu/faculty-staff-directory/wendy-smith/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wendy Smith</a> says this binary way of confronting dilemmas contains a trap. She offers a different way to think about difficult choices, one that opens unexpected possibilities.”</em></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Tech Readings  </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://dev.to/jeroendedauw/advice-for-junior-developers-30am" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Advice for Junior Developers</a> – I wish I read this before talking to a bunch of junior devs a couple days ago. This article presents an important list of things that budding devs should start assimilating as part of their work. While many of us would feel this is intuitive, actioning it needs intentional practice.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow"><p>Someone with half your IQ is making 10x as you because they aren&#8217;t smart enough to doubt themselves.</p><cite>Ed Latimore</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings 14/Oct/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/10/14/friday-musings-14-oct-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 08:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’ve read. 3 Types of Meetings — and How to Do Each One Well – A refresher on how to handle meetings in a hybrid [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-is-layout-6 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Articles I’ve read.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://hbr.org/2022/09/3-types-of-meetings-and-how-to-do-each-one-well" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3 Types of Meetings — and How to Do Each One Well</a> – A refresher on how to handle meetings in a hybrid work model and how to ensure everyone can make the most of meetings.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Videos I Watched</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4hg1K0HD5Xo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Locked in a machine for 70 years</a> – Inspiring story of Paul Alexander, a polio survivor, who beat the odds and continues to be one of last surviving people living in an Iron Lung. It was emotional for me to know the hardships he had to overcome and still achieve things many can only dream about.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Podcasts I Listened</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://freakonomics.com/podcast/whats-wrong-with-holding-a-grudge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">No Stupid Questions &#8211; What&#8217;s wrong with holding a grudge?</a> – Another good conversation between Angela and Stephen where they talk about the emotional cost of grudge, how to let go of resentment, whether Apologies work.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Tech Readings  </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://makeavideo.studio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Make-A-Video</a> &amp; <a href="https://phenaki.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Phenaki</a> – Following Meta AI’s announcement 2 weeks ago of their “text to Video” generator, Google has release 2 of their own text to video generators this week. It’s amazing to see the acceleration in text to image, video and audio models. Looking forward to a full-fledged movie created by AI only with story prompts!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow"><p>It does not matter how slowly you go as long as you do not stop.</p><cite>Confucius</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings 08/Oct/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/10/09/friday-musings-08-oct-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 04:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’ve read. How to have better Arguments?&#160;– Arguments are inevitable these days and it&#8217;s extremely important for us to understand the basics around arguing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-is-layout-7 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Articles I’ve read.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-have-arguments-that-change-minds-including-your-own" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to have better Arguments?</a>&nbsp;– Arguments are inevitable these days and it&#8217;s extremely important for us to understand the basics around arguing (why/how/when etc.). In addition to arming us with information, knowing these will help both us and the other person to get more out of the exchange.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Videos I Watched</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/shankar_vedantam_you_don_t_actually_know_what_your_future_self_wants" target="_blank" rel="noopener">You don&#8217;t actually know what your future self wants</a>&nbsp;–&nbsp;Profound talk by one of my favorite podcast hosts, Shankar Vedantam, this video is about coming to terms that our future self will not make the same decisions as we are making today and learning some ways to help craft the person we are to become.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Places I’ve Travelled</em></strong></h3>



<p>Completed a long pending trip to Sikkim &amp; Darjeeling with the family.&nbsp; I&#8217;d highly recommend this as a place to visit for your next vacation. Sikkim is mind bogglingly beautiful with friendly people, interesting culture and history. Did you know that Sikkim was an independent country/Kingdom until 1975 when it was officially annexed and made the 22nd state of India.&nbsp;<a href="https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipOaG2S8tci_elc8ogyIvUJq8d0W5Y0seDuLR9eugvLR0hgy96lpLRkgnpCvJsCuyw?key=NzNRU2xJX0JhaERVc0lKVHp6OGRMNUxRME5LZUpB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Here&#8217;s some photos from my trip.</a></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://blog.pragmaticengineer.com/resiliency-in-distributed-systems/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Resiliency in Distributed Systems</a>&nbsp;&#8211; A good read on some fundamentals to consider when working on large scale systems specifically around downstream and upstream resiliency.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow"><p>Give the ones you love wings to fly, roots to come back, and reasons to stay.</p><cite>Dalai Lama</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musing 23/Sep/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/09/23/friday-musing-23-sep-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 05:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’ve read. Why It’s Hard To Learn From Our Mistakes – Though a clickbait-y title, there&#8217;s some key information shared in this article around common [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-is-layout-8 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Articles I’ve read.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.worth.com/why-smart-people-make-bad-decisions-why-its-hard-to-learn-from-our-mistakes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Why It’s Hard To Learn From Our Mistakes</a> – Though a clickbait-y title, there&#8217;s some key information shared in this article around common reasons for why it&#8217;s easy to make mistakes and how neuroplasticity can help overcome this.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Videos I Watched</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E6bVBH9y5O8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Biggest Myth About Climate Change</a> – With increased occurrences of extreme climate events, it’s hard to ignore the fact that climate change is real, and we need concrete action to minimize its adverse effects. In this video, Joe explains how Climate change naysayers are incorrect and why there’s nothing “natural” about climate change.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Podcasts I Listened</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://allinchamathjason.libsyn.com/e96-adobe-acquires-figma-for-20b-tpb-spac-fedex-ceos-recession-warning-macro-picture-more" target="_blank" rel="noopener">All-In &#8211; Adobe acquires Figma for $20B, TPB SPAC, FedEx CEO&#8217;s recession warning, macro picture &amp; more</a> – It takes some getting used to this podcast format of multi-participant discussion on varied topics, but once you are over it, you’ll come to appreciate the depth of analysis on topics and the amount of critical thinking involved and the kind of questions raised. In this episode Chamath, sacks and others dissect the Adobe-Figma deal &amp; fears of a global recession.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><em>Tech Readings  </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://typefully.com/DanHollick/qr-codes-T7tLlNi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QR Codes!</a> In fascinating that the Toyota subsidiary that invented the QR code never exercised its patent and released it for free making these pixelated blobs omnipresent and so useful these days.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow"><p>The ability to observe without evaluating is the highest form of intelligence.</p><cite>J Krishnamurti</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
